A Finding Aid to the Winnie Dodge Papers, circa 1913-1931, 2010-2012, in the Archives of American Art AAA.dodgwinn
Archives of American Art
Winnie Dodge papers
circa 1913-1931
2010-2012
AAA.dodgwinn
Archives of American Art
0.4 Linear feet
The papers of Winnie Dodge measure 0.4 linear feet and date from circa 1913 to 1931 and 2010 to 2012. The collection contains photographs of the Walter L. Dodge House in West Hollywood, CA and documents Winnie Dodge's life through travel journals, diaries, and photographs.
Dodge, Winnie K.
Scope and Contents note
The papers of Winnie Dodge measure 0.4 linear feet and date from circa 1913 to 1931 and 2010 to 2012. The collection contains photographs of the Walter L. Dodge House in West Hollywood, California and documents Winnie Dodge's life through travel journals, diaries, and photographs.
The photographs of the Walter L. Dodge House include views of the exterior and interior of the house as well as the grounds. Winnie Dodge's travel journals document the Second Great African Cruise taken in 1927 and the Round the World Cruise taken from 1929 to 1930. Dodge's diaries document her life from 1922 to 1930. One passport belonged to Luna Kies Steiner, Dodge's friend and travel companion. Photographs consist of three portraits, one art photograph, and a photograph of Dodge's son, Don, at age ten in 1913. Also included is one compact disc containing scans of photographs included in this collection, images from web sites, and historical information about the Dodge House.
Arrangement note
This collection is arranged as 1 series.
Series 1: Winnie Dodge Papers, circa 1913-1931, 2010-2012 (Box 1; 0.4 linear feet)
Conditions Governing Access note
Use of original papers requires an appointment.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Donated in 2012 by Roger Humphries, who inherited the papers from an unknown relative who had ties to the Dodge family.
Related Archival Materials note
The Archives of American Art also has material relating to the Walter L. Dodge house in the papers of architectual historian Esther McCoy, including a 1965 film created by McCoy as a part of her effort to save Dodge House from destruction.
Biographical/Historical note
Winnie K. Dodge (1868-1939) was married to Walter L. Dodge, who patented "Tiz", a medicine for tired feet. They had a son, Don, in 1903. The Dodge House, designed by architect Irving Gill, was built for the Dodges in 1916. Winnie and Walter eventually separated and sold the Dodge House in 1924. Winnie moved to 455 North Sycamore Avenue in Los Angeles. She traveled extensively to South America, Africa, Europe, and Asia, often traveling with friend Luna Kies Steiner.
Steiner, Luna Kies; Diaries; Photographs; Travel journals; Walter L. Dodge House (Los Angeles, Calif.)
- Winnie Dodge Papers, 2010-2012; circa 1913-1931; Series 1; 0.4 Linear feet Box 1
  Scope and Contents note
  This series documents Winnie Dodge's life, primarily during the 1920s, and the Dodge House. Two diaries that log Dodge's daily activities are included. Also found are two travel journals which describes Dodge's Second Great African Cruise which lasted over three months and her Round the World Cruise which lasted over four months. A passenger list and appraisal letter regarding Dodge's apartment on 455 North Sycamore Avenue in Los Angeles were originally inside the Round the World Cruise travel journal. Also included is the passport of Luna Kies Steiner, who was Dodge's friend and travel companion. The passport originally contained the calling card, postcard, and three locket-size photographs of a young girl. Personal photographs of Dodge's include a photograph of her son Don at the age of 10 and three portraits of unidentified women. Photographs of the Dodge House show the interior and exterior of the house, the garden, and grounds. Photographs of the Dodge House are also on one compact disc which also include images from web sites, and historical information about the Dodge House.
  - Diary, 1922-1925 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Diary, 1926-1930 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Travel Journal, Second Great African Cruise, 1927 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Travel Journal, Maps from Inside Second Great African Cruise Travel Journal, 1927 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Travel Journal, Round the World Cruise, 1929-1930 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Passenger List, Round the World Cruise, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Passport of Luna Kies Steiner, 1929-1931 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Items from Inside Steiner Passport, circa 1913-1920 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Photographs, Personal, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Photograph, Don Dodge, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Photographs, Dodge House Exterior and Grounds, circa 1920s (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Photographs, Interior of the Dodge House, circa 1920s (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Dodge House Images and Information, 2010-2012 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    Includes 1 CD-R